Guide to the William F. Anselm Collection of New York University Memorabilia MC.248
New York University Archives
William F. Anselm Collection of New York University Memorabilia
1932-1938
1935-1938
New York University Archives
Anselm, William F.
MC.248
0.75 Linear Feet in one half manuscript box and one card box
The William F. Anselm Collection of New York University Memorabilia contains ephemera and publications dating from William F. Anselm's tenure as a student at New York University (Engineering '36). As a student, Anselm was active in Greek life as a member of the Delta Phi fraternity and the Inter-Fraternity Council. He was also a member of Scabbard and Blade, a military honor society, and the ROTC Rifle and Pistol Club.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Office of Alumni Relations in circa 2014. The accession number associated with this collection is 14.032.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged chronologically in two series:
Series I: Printed Materials
Series II: Objects
Biographical Note
William F. Anselm was born in Staten Island in 1914. He studied Electrical Engineering at New York University, graduating with a Bachelor of Science degree in 1936. As a student, Anselm was active in Greek life as a member of the Delta Phi fraternity and the Inter-Fraternity Council. He was also a member of Scabbard and Blade, a military honor society, and the ROTC Rifle and Pistol Club. After graduating from NYU, he worked for General Electric.
Sources:
1. New York University. The Violet. New York: Graduating Class of 1936, 1936. New York University Archives, Elmer Holmes Bobst Library.
2. New York University College of Engineering. Directory of Alumni. University Heights, New York: New York University, June 1950.
Related Materials
Guide to the Albert W. Ferris Papers (MC 183)
Guide to the Ira S. Kaye Scrapbook (MC 80)
Scope and Contents
The collection contains ephemera and publications dating from William F. Anselm's tenure as a student at New York University (Engineering '36). Most of the materials were created by NYU between 1932 and 1938. These materials include invitations and programs for events hosted by the university or groups associated with it, including the military honor society Scabbard and Blade, the ROTC program, and the Engineering Societies. Other materials include assorted issues of the New York University Medley, a student magazine, NYU football ticket stubs and programs, and a purple quill pen labeled "NYU." A few items in the collection were not created by NYU, most of which are programs from New York City theatrical productions that Anselm presumably attended.
Theater -- New York (State) -- New York.; New York University. School of Engineering and Science; New York University -- Students; New York University. Reserve Officer Training Corps -- History; Delta Phi; Scabbard and Blade Fraternity
- Series I: Printed Material, 1932-1938; 0.25 Linear Feet in one half manuscript box
  Scope and Contents
  Series I includes invitations and programs for events hosted by the university or groups associated with it, including the military honor society Scabbard and Blade, the ROTC program, and the Engineering Societies. Other materials include assorted issues of the New York University Medley, a student magazine, NYU football ticket stubs and programs
  - New York University Medley, various issues, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Program for Autumn Crocus (play), 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - NYU Engineering Societies Techni-Frolic invitation, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - ROTC Formal Dinner Dance programs, 1935-07-13 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Scabbard and Blade annual military ball, 1935, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ROTC Annual Field Day invitation and program, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Baccalaureate Service programs, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Commencement program and invitation, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Inter-Fraternity Council Informal Dance, 1936, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Playbill for Yes, My Darling Daughter, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - NYU Football ticket stubs and schedule, 1937, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Delta Phi Summer Formal invitations, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Program for Naughty-Naught (play), undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Waldorf-Astoria cocktail napkin, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - East 148th St. Restaurant Corp. business card, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series II: Objects, 1935-1936, undated; 0.5 Linear Feet in one card box
  Series II includes a badge with ribbons for representation of the Floor Committee for the 1936 Military ball; a name badge with ribbon for the 1936 Engineering Demonstration Day; a commemorative football button; and a purple quill pen labeled "NYU."
  - Floor Committee, Military Ball name badge and ribbon, 1935-04-26 (Box 2)
  - Engineering Demonstration Day name badge and ribbon, 1936 March 7 (Box 2)
  - "N.Y.U. Beat Fordham" button, undated (Box 2)
  - NYU quill pen, undated (Box 2)